<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fintech Musings</title>
    <link>https://pandichef.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Fintech Musings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 14:06:21 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pandichef.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cryptocurrency Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>https://pandichef.github.io/note/cryptocurrency-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 14:06:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pandichef.github.io/note/cryptocurrency-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>Statistics Stats as of 9/10/20
   Currency Ticker Market Cap Volume (24hrs) Coinbase Popularity Avg Hold Time (days) Short Description     USD Coin USDC $1.8bn $462.5mm 18 15 Coinbase&amp;rsquo;s stablecoin   0x ZRX $340.6mm $46.7mm 10 102 -   Bitcoin BTC $191.4bn $33.5bn 1 92 -   Algorand ALGO $440.4mm $264.5mm 21 13 Proof-of-Stake   Augur REP $187.4mm $11.mm 23 17 Prediction Markets   Band Protocol BAND $184.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Crowdfunding?</title>
      <link>https://pandichef.github.io/note/what-is-crowdfunding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 14:32:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pandichef.github.io/note/what-is-crowdfunding/</guid>
      <description>Traditional Offerings Reg D Federal law only allows Accredited Investors to legally invest in startups using Regulation D 506. Accredited Investors have no limits.
Accredited investors:
 earn more than $200,000 per year, or a joint income of $300,000, in the last two years and expect the same this year. or, have a net worth exceeding $1 million not including their home  Reg A+ Non-accredited investors may legally invest no more than 10% of their income or net worth - whichever is greater.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do interest rates continue to grind lower?</title>
      <link>https://pandichef.github.io/post/solow-growth-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 11:59:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pandichef.github.io/post/solow-growth-model/</guid>
      <description>Many people have asked me recently why interest rates continue to grind lower. As can be seen in Figure 1 below, when viewed over the course of 3 decades, interest rates have declined almost linearly since 1982. In fact, the same trend holds true for many western countries. Why might that be the case?
Macrotrends Data Download10 Year Treasury Rate - 54 Year Historical ChartDISCLAIMER AND TERMS OF USE: HISTORICAL DATA IS PROVIDED &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Skewness and Kurtosis Don&#39;t Matter</title>
      <link>https://pandichef.github.io/post/generalized-sharpe-ratio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 14:23:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pandichef.github.io/post/generalized-sharpe-ratio/</guid>
      <description>The Sharpe Ratio is one of the most common performance metrics for both individual stocks and portfolios. However, a more natural choice for a portfolio performance metric is the ratio of the expected return to some Value-at-Risk of the return distribution, which can be characterized as a Generalized Sharpe Ratio i.e., $$ GSR \equiv \lim_{\alpha \to 0} \frac{\mu}{V_\alpha(\mu=0,\sigma,s,k,&amp;hellip;)} $$ where \(V_{\alpha}()\) is the Value-at-Risk, \(\alpha\) is the probability threshold and \(\mu\), \(\sigma\), \(s\), etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Common Sense Approach to Portfolio Theory</title>
      <link>https://pandichef.github.io/post/naive-portfolio-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 12:05:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pandichef.github.io/post/naive-portfolio-theory/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Traditional portfolio theory employs an optimization strategy that involves maximizing a expected portfolio&amp;rsquo;s Sharpe Ratio given asset Sharpe Ratios and a correlation matrix. Levy and Duchin (2009), however, demonstrate that optimal weights don&amp;rsquo;t significantly outperform a naive 1/N optimization strategy.
The problem with weights is that they are heavily dependent on Sharpe Ratio estimatation. If a stock has a 0.99 correlation versus the market and has the highest Sharpe Ratio amongst all assets under consideration, then portfolio optimization would suggest that 100% of the portfolio should be in that single asset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Margin of Safety vs Volatility</title>
      <link>https://pandichef.github.io/post/margin-of-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 23:17:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pandichef.github.io/post/margin-of-safety/</guid>
      <description>In Theory There are two common models of conceptualizing the risk associated with a stock:
 The Margin of Safety Principal popularized by Benjamin Graham Asset returns volatility  The former can be characterized as a subjective assessment of how much downside risk is associated with a stock. In other words, it&amp;rsquo;s a consideration of the potential losses if an investor&amp;rsquo;s thesis is incorrect and/or if the worst case scenario is realized.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>